ISURI DEVINDI

Department of Computer Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka





My primary research interest is on developing low-energy Human-Al collaborative systems for realtime, context-aware interactions, to enhance embodied AI interactions in everyday environments, particularly in **healthcare** applications.

EDUCATION

BSc.Eng (Hons.) in Computer Engineering

University of Peradeniya 2018 Nov - 2023 Dec

G.C.E. Advanced Level Examination

Hillwood College, Kandy

2004 - 2017

First Class Hons.

Class rank: 1/415

GPA: 4.00/4.00

Z-Score: 2.2768 District rank: 6/2784

National Rank: 113 / 32075

PUBLICATIONS

[J 3] IEEE Access

Multimodal Deep Convolutional Neural Network Pipeline for Al-Assisted Early Detection of Oral Cancer



Isuri Devindi, Dinura Dissanayake, Sashini Liyanage, Achintha Harshamal, Dhanushki Mapitigama, Nadisha Piyarathne, Kalani Hettiarachchi, Sumudu Rasnayaka, Ruwan Jayasinghe, Roshan Ragel, Isuru Nawinne

Contribution: Conceptualization, Methodology, Software, Validation, Writing - Original Draft. Review & Editing

[J 2] Nature Scientific Reports

A Novel ECG Compression Algorithm Using PWM-Integrated Quantization for Low-Power Real-Time Monitoring



Isuri Devindi, Sashini Liyanage, Titus Jayarathna, Janaka Alawatugoda, Roshan Ragel Contribution: Conceptualization, Methodology, Software, Validation, Writing - Original Draft, Review & Editing

Oral Oncology

[J 1] Science Direct Comprehensive Dataset of Annotated White Light Images of Oral Cavity and Novel Web Tool for Image Annotation



N. S. Piyarathne, S.N. Liyanage, R.M.S.G.K. Rasnayaka, P.V.K.S. Hettiarachchi, G.A.I. Devindi, F.B.A.H. Francis, D.M.D.R. Dissanayake, R.A.N.S. Ranasinghe, M.B.D. Pavithya, I. Nawinne, R.G. Ragel, R.D. Jayasinghe

Contribution: Software, Data curation

[C 1] IEEE: Moratuwa Engineering Research Conference 2024

EEG Based Brain-Computer Interface for Inner Speech Classification

Praveen Dhananjaya, Isurika Adikari, Sumudu Lakmali, Isuri Devindi, Sashini Liyanage, Mahanama Wickramasingha, Theekshana Dissanayake, Roshan G. Ragel, Isuru Nawinne

Contribution: Writing - Review & Editing, Visualization



[C 2] IEEE: Moratuwa Engineering Research Conference 2024

Self-Paced Brain-Computer Interface on Sensorimotor Rhythms for **Controlling Virtual Objects**

A.D. Athapattu, P.S.B. Dassanayake, G.S.C. Nanayakkara, S.N. Liyanage, G.A.I. **Devindi**, Roshan G. Ragel, Theekshana Dissanayake, Isuru Nawinne

Contribution: Writing - Review & Editing, Visualization



[C 3] IEEE: Moratuwa Engineering Research Conference 2024

Decoding Non-Motor Imagery Tasks with Non-Invasive EEG Based Brain Computer Interface: A Review

Sumudu Lakmali, Praveen Dhananjaya, Isurika Adikari, **Isuri Devindi**, Sashini Liyanage, Mahanama Wickramasingha, Theekshana Dissanayake, Roshan G. Ragel, Isuru Nawinne **Contribution:** Writing - Review & Editing



EXPERIENCE

2024 Jan Instructor

- Present Department of Computer Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka

Computer Architecture (CO224), Image Processing (CO543), Operating Systems

(CO327), Python Programming (CO1010)

2023 Jan Visiting Research Assistant Supervised by Prof. Archan Misra

- 2023 May Pervasive Sensing & Systems Lab, Singapore Management University

Exploring spatiotemporal compressive sensing techniques for event-based **neuromorphic** vision sensor data fed into and processed by Spiking Neural Networks (View project details).

2021 - 2022 **Teaching Assistant**

Department of Computer Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka

Embedded Systems (CO321), Data Structures and Algorithms (CO322), Programming and

Networking (CO253), Programming Methodology (CO222)

2021 - Present **Technical Article Writer (Part-time)**

Enlear Pvt. Ltd

Writing technical content on computer vision, machine learning, and web development.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Best Paper Award in Biomedical Engineering Track at MERCon 2024

Received the Best Paper Award for the paper **EEG Based Brain-Computer Interface for Inner Speech Classification** in the Biomedical Engineering track at the Moratuwa Engineering Research Conference (MERCon) 2024.

2024 Gold medal for excellence in Computer Engineering

Awarded for the best performance at the Department of Computer Engineering, University

of Peradeniya (Out of 60)

2024 Prize for Engineering Mathematics

Prof. T.D.M.A. Samuel prize awarded for the enthusiasm and excellence in Engineering

Mathematics at the Faculty of Engineering, University of Peradeniya (Out of 415)

2023 Bronze Award in NBQSA 2023 | National ICT Awards

Bronze award in Tertiary Student Projects (Technology) (Out of 46 teams) for the project

"Oral Cavity Image Annotation and Cancer Prediction from White Light Images"

2022 IEEEXtreme 16.0 | 24 hour global algorithmic programming competition

Team Name - bitLasagna, Country Rank - 27, Global Rank - 427

(Out of 14600+ participants)

2022 ACES Coders V9.0 | 12 hour national algorithmic programming competition

The biggest annual on-ground inter-university 12-hour coding competition in Sri Lanka

organized by the University of Peradeniya.

Team Name – Zblunt, Country Rank – 6 (Out of 100+ teams)

OTHER PROJECTS

2023 Jan - Efficient Event Stream Compression for Low-Energy Neuromorphic Systems | Individual



 \Box

Under the supervision of <u>Prof. Archan Misra</u>, explored compressive sensing techniques (rate coding, latency coding, delta modulation, event and time window slicing, voxel cubes) to convert event-based neuromorphic vision sensor data into 2D frames for low-energy spiking neural networks (SNNs) and evaluated their impact on classification and object detection performance.

Technology: snnTorch, PyTorch, Python

2022 Jan - Reconstructing Highly Degraded License Plates | Group
2022 March Demonstration of the efficacy of traditional image processing techniq

Demonstration of the efficacy of traditional image processing techniques to reconstruct highly degraded images of license plates obtained from CCTV footage, when the source of

degradation is unknown.

Contribution: Exploring traditional image processing techniques such as Otsu thresholding, Morphological transformation, Contouring, Spatial and Frequency domain filtering and Degradation modeling(Wiener Filter) for image reconstruction.

Technology: Python, OpenCV

2021 Remote Proctoring System | Group

A single device with video streaming facility that integrates the hardware and software components needed to conduct virtual proctoring of an examination in a university.

Contribution: Designing a scalable web application for administrators of the university and proctors of examinations. Developing the hardware solution for the device using a Raspberry Pi microcon-

Technology: React.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Node.js

2020 8-bit single cycle processor | Group

An 8-bit single cycle CPU with associated memory hierarchy. The processor includes an ALU, register file, control logic, forwarding unit, data memory, data cache, instruction memory and instruction cache.

Technology: Verilog-HDL

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES & LEADERSHIPS HELD

2020 - 2024 Member of the Web Consultation team of University of Peradeniya

Group focused on improving university's digital presence

2023 Committee member of the Association of Computer Engineering Students

(ACES) of the University of Peradeniya

Contributed to the team that designed algorithmic programming questions for the ACES

Coders v10.0 competition.

2022 - 2023 Secretary of IET on Campus of the University of Peradeniya

2021 - 2022 President of the Music Society of the University of Peradeniya

2022 - 2023 Compère at various events at the University of Peradeniya

REFERENCES

Prof. Roshan G. Ragel | roshanr@eng.pdn.ac.lk

Head of Department, Department of Computer Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka **Dr. Isuru Nawinne** | isurunawinne@eng.pdn.ac.lk

Senior Lecturer, Department of Computer Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka **Prof. Archan Misra** | archanm@smu.edu.sg

Vice Provost (Research), School of Computing & Information Systems, Singapore Management University, Singapore